Guide to the Lawrence Tibbett Collection ARS.0041
Archive of Recorded Sound
- Shellac and Instantaneous Recordings: 1937-1945, 47 78 rpm discs (Box 2)
  - [Texaco] Star Theater, WABC, 9:30-10:00 p.m.:, 03-18-1945; 4.0 78 rpm discs; 4 12" glass-based instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs. Disc 1 is cracked. (Box 2, Discs 37-40)
    Lawrence Tibbett, Jane Froman, vocalists; Alex Templeton, piano; orchestra and chorus, [conducted by] Al Goodman.
    Universal Recording Company.
    Disc 37 is damaged and is stored separately from the rest of the Tibbett Collection.
  - [Your Hit Parade] CBS Line, 9:00-9:45 p.m.:, 03-24-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" glass-based instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double sided disc and 1 singe-sided disc. (Box 2, Discs 41-42)
    Berlin, Irving, 1888-1989. Alexander's ragtime band -- Shannon, J. R. (James Royce), 1881-1946. That's an Irish lullaby -- Accentuate the positive (music by Harold Arlen)
  - [Your Hit Parade] CBS Line, 9:00-9:45 p.m. (copy 2):, 03-24-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double-sided disc and 1 single-sided disc. (Box 2, Discs 43-44)
    Berlin, Irving, 1888-1989. Alexander's ragtime band -- Shannon, J. R. (James Royce), 1881-1946. That's an Irish lullaby. (Toora-loora) -- Accentuate the positive (music by Harold Arlen)
  - Philco Hall of Fame: WJZ, 6:00-7:00 p.m.:, 03-25-1945; 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc. (Box 2, Disc 45)
    "Lawrence Tibbett spot"
  - [Your Hit Parade]: WABC, 9:00-9:45 p.m.:, 03-31-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double-sided disc, 1 single-sided disc. (Box 2, Discs 46-47)
    I'm beginning to see the light (words and music by Don George, Johnny Hodges, Duke Ellington, and Harry James) -- Gershwin, George, 1898-1937. Porgy and Bess. It ain't necessarily so -- Berlin, Irving, 1888-1989. As thousands cheer. Easter parade.
- Shellac and Acetate Recordings: April-July 1945, Undated Recordings, and Miscellaneous Recordings, 04-23-1945 -- 07-21-1945; 55.0 78 rpm discs (Box 3)
  - [Your Hit Parade] WABC, 9:00-9:45 p.m.:, 04-07-1945; 4.0 78 rpm discs; 4 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 2 double-sided discs, 2 single-sided discs. (Box 3, Discs 1-4)
    Cohan, George M. (George Michael), 1878-1942. Over there -- Handy, W. C. (William Christopher), 1873-1958. Saint Louis blues -- I'm beginning to see the light [words and music by Don George, Johnny Hodges, Duke Ellington, and Harry James]
    Includes 2 copies of each disc.
    Rockhill Recording (copy 1) Universal Recording Company (copy 2)
  - Special PGM with Lawrence Tibbett., 04-14-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" glass-based instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double-sided disc, and 1 single-sided disc. (Box 3, Discs 5-6)
    Home on the range -- Deep river -- Battle hymn
    National Broadcasting Co. Reference Recording Instantaneous: 48010, 48011, 48012
  - [Your Hit Parade]: WABC, 9:00-9:45 p.m.:, 04/21-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" glass-based instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double-sided disc and 1 single-sided disc. (Box 3, Discs 7-8)
    Gershwin, George, 1898-1937. Porgy and Bess. I got plenty o' nuttin' -- Get your gear on [words and music by Al Carbuto] -- I'm beginning to see the light [words and music by Don George, Johnny Hodges, Duke Ellington, and Harry James]
  - [Your Hit Parade] CBS Line, 9:00-9:45 p.m.:, 04-21-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double-sided disc and 1 single-sided disc. (Box 3, Discs 9-10)
    Universal Recording
  - United Nations: WEAF, RCA, 4:30-5:00 p.m.:, 04-22-1945; 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" glass-based instantaneous 78 rpm single-sided sound disc. (Box 3, Disc 11)
    [Music America loves best]
  - [RCA Music you want] WEAF, 4:30-5:00 p.m.:, 04-22-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double sided disc, 1 single-sided disc. (Box 3, Discs 12-13)
    Tommy-lad (music by E. J. Margetson) -- Porter, Cole, 1891-1964. Jubilee. Begin the beguine -- Foster, Stephen Collins, 1826-1864. Jeanie with the light brown hair.
  - [Your Hit Parade] WEAF, 9:30-10:00 p.m.:, 04-23-1945; 4.0 78 rpm discs; 4 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 2 double-sided discs, 2 single-sided discs. (Box 3, Discs 14-17)
    "Information please"
  - [Hit Parade] CBS Line, 9:00-9:45 p.m.:, 04-28-1945; 4.0 78 rpm discs; 4 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 2 double-sided discs, 2 single-sided discs. (Box 3, Discs 18-21)
    El rancho grande -- [Coslow, Sam, 1902-1982]: Sing you sinners -- I'm beginning to see the light (words and music by Don George, Johnny Hodges, Duke Ellington, and Harry James)
    Includes 2 copies of this program.
    Universal Recording Company (copy 1) Rockhill Recording (copy 2)
  - [Your Hit Parade] CBS, 9:00-9:45 p.m.:, 06-02-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double-sided disc, 1 single-sided disc. (Box 3, Discs 22-23)
    Gershwin, George, 1898-1937. Porgy and Bess. It ain't necessarily so -- Don't fence me in (music by Cole Porter) -- Sentimental journey (music by Bud Green)
  - [Your Hit Parade] CBS Line, 9:00-9:45 p.m.:, 06-02-1945; 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" instantaneous 78 rpm single-sided sound disc. (Box 3, Disc 24)
    Sentimental journey [words and music by Bud Green]
  - Hit Parade, WABC:, 06-09-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double-sided disc, 1 single-sided disc. (Box 3, Discs 25-26)
    Jingle, jangle, jingle -- Old man river -- Sentimental journey [words and music by Bud Green]
  - Milton Berle Show, WABC, 10:30-11:00 p.m.:, 06-13-1945; 3.0 78 rpm discs; 3 12" instantaneous 78 rpm double-sided sound discs. Label from Side 3 missing. (Box 3, Discs 27-29)
    Lawrence Tibbett, baritone.
    "Milton Berle Show"
    Universal recording Company.
  - [Your Hit Parade] CBS Line, 9:00-9:30 p.m.:, 06-16-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double-sided disc, 1 single-sided disc. (Box 3, Discs 30-31)
    Labels detached from discs stored in separate envelopes with discs.
    Bellbottom trousers -- Cloe (label detached from disc) -- Sentimental journey (music by Bud Green)(label detached from disc)
    Universal Recording Company
  - [Your Hit Parade] WABC, 9:00-9:45 p.m.:, 06-16-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double-sided disc, 1 single-sided disc. (Box 3, Discs 32-33)
    Bellbottom trousers -- Chloe -- Sentimental journey (music by Bud Green)
    Rockhill Recording
  - WOR, 3:30-4:00 p.m.:, 06-17-1945; 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" instantaneous 78 rpm single-sided sound disc. (Box 3, Disc 34)
    Label detached from disc stored in separate envelopes with discs.
    Get out & buy those "E" bonds (words and music by Herman Hupfeld)(label detached from disc)
  - [Your Hit Parade] CBS, 9-9:30 p.m.:, 06-23-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double-sided disc, 1 single-sided disc. (Box 3, Discs 35-36)
    Get out and buy those "E" bonds (words and music by Herman Hupfeld) -- Bell bottom trousers (music by Moe Jaffe) -- Sentimental journey (music by Bud Green)
  - [Your Hit Parade] CBS, 9:00-9:45 p.m.:, 06-23-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double sided disc, 1 single-sided disc. (Box 3, Discs 37-38)
  - [Your Hit Parade] CBS-Line, 9-9:45 p.m.:, 06-30-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double-sided disc, 1 single-sided disc. (Box 3, Discs 39-40)
    Accentuate the positive (music by Harold Arlen) -- The cassons go rolling along -- Sentimental journey (music by Bud Green)
  - [Your Hit Parade] WABC, 9-9:15 p.m.:, 07-07-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double-sided disc, 1 single-sided disc. (Box 3, Discs 41-42)
    Gershwin, George, 1898-1937. Porgy and Bess. I got plenty o' nuttin' -- Romberg, Sigmund, 1887-1951. Desert song. One alone -- Sentimental journey (music by Bud Green)
  - [Your Hit Parade] WABC, 9-9:45 p.m.:, 07-14-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double-sided disc, 1 single-sided disc. (Box 3, Discs 43-44)
    Handy, W. C. (William Christopher), 1873-1958. Saint Louis blues -- Army Air Corps -- Dream (words and music by Johnny Mercer)
  - Hit Parade, WABC, 9-9:45 p.m.:, 07-21-1945; 4.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double-sded disc, 1 single-sided disc (2 copies of each disc). (Box 3, Discs 45-48)
    Deacon Jones [music by Johnny Lange] -- [Stothart, Herbert, 1885-1949: Rogue song, from the motion picture The rogue song] -- Dream [words and music by Johnny Mercer]
    Universal Recording Co. (copy 1) Rockhill Recording (copy 2)
    Copy 1: All labels are detached and stored in separate envelopes which accompany discs.
  - Somerveil, Arthur: Kingdom by the sea -- Kern, Jerome, 1885-1945. Show boat. Ol' man river., 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc. (Box 3, Disc 49)
    Lawrence Tibbett, baritone; Stewart Wille, piano accompaniment.
    Victor Special Record: Cs 74704-Cs 74705; A 74704 2 VE, A 74705 2 VE (matrix)
    Hammerstein, Oscar, 1895-1960; Kern, Jerome, 1885-1945; Poe, Edgar Allan, 1809-1849; Somervell, Arthur, Sir, 1863-193; Wille, Stewart
  - Del Riego, Teresa, 1876-1968. Star was his candle., 3.0 78 rpm discs; 1 single-sided 10" 78 rpm shellac sound disc (3 copies). (Box 3, Discs 50-52)
    Disc 52 is damaged and is stored separately from the rest of the Tibbett Collection.
    Hoare, Florence
  - Spell., 1.0 78 rpm disc; 10" single-sided shellac 78 rpm sound disc. (Box 3, Disc 53)
    Handwritten in pencil in place of label: Spell. Possibly the song "Amigo" from the film Under your spell.
    Victor: 97755-1 (matrix)
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1892-1950: Poem & prayer for an invading army., 06/06/1944; 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc. (Box 3, Disc 54)
    Ronald Coleman reading Poem & prayer for an invading army by Edna St. Vincent Millay. Written especially for the National Broadcasting Co. and recorded for the NBC 24-hour D-Day Broadcast, Tuesday, June 6, 1944.
    NBC: ND4/MC/5606--ND4/MC/5607; ND4-MC-5606-1B, ND4-MC-5607-1D (matrix)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Falstaff. Quand'ero paggio del Duca di Norfolk -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello. Era la notte., 1904-1908; 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" double-sided instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc. (Box 3, Disc 55)
    1st work performed by Victor Manuel, originally recorded in 1904. 2nd work performed by Antonio Magini-Coletti and Elisa Petro, originally recorded Oct. 1, 1908.
    RCA DeLuxe Recording.
    Magini-Coletti, Antonio, 1855-1912; Manuel, Victor; Petro, Elisa
  - Gershwin, George, 1898-1937. Porgy and Bess. Selections., 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc. (Box 3, Disc 56)
    Performed by Lawrence Tibbett, baritone; Helen Jepson, soprano; chorus and orchestra conducted by Alexander Smallens. Recorded under the supervision of the composer.
    Contents: Scene: Summertime and Crap game - A woman is a sometime thing - Bess, you is my woman now.
    RCA Victor: C 25-3, C 25-4; 11879-A VE, 11879-B VE (matrix nos.)
    Disc is damaged and is stored separately from the rest of the Tibbett Collection.
    Jepson, Helen, 1904-1997
- Audio tape, 1.0 7" open reel tape (Box 4)
  - Tape of Lawrence Tibbett, Sr., 1.0 sound tape reel; 1 7" tape reel, playback at 7 1/2 ips. (Box 4, Reel 1)
    Performed by Lawrence Tibbett, Sr.
    Contents:
    Stothart, Herbert, 1885-1949. Rogue song. Rogue song -- Stothart, Herbert, 1885-1949. Rogue song. Narrative -- Stothart, Herbert, 1885-1949. Tramps at sea -- McHugh, Jimmy, 1894-1969. Cuban love song -- Yradier, Sebastián, 1809-1865. Paloma -- Stothart, Herbert, 1885-1949. Rogue song. When I'm looking at you.
    Tape prepared by Larry Tibbett Jr.
    Stothart, Herbert, 1885-1949
- Miscellaneous Documents, 3.0 folders (Box 5)
  - Collection Inventories, 1.0 folder; 6 leaves of paper, 8 1/2" x 11" with 4 leaves in typescript and 2 leaves with photocopied typescript. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Folder contains two inventories of the collection: (1) Typescript with handwritten additions; (2) Photocopy of typescript with quantities of discs listed and donor's contact information handwritten at the end.
  - Tape inventory, 1.0 folder; 13 4' x 6" index cards. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Contents listings of 13 tape reels in Tibbett's personal collection, with each card containing the contents of one tape reel. Information is handwritten in pencil with occasional additions in black ink or red pencil.
  - Articles by Lawrence Tibbett, 1.0 folder; 27 leaves, 8 1/2" x 11" paper; photocopied on one side of each sheet. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Folder contains photocopies of four published articles by Lawrence Tibbett: (1) Along the glory road; (2) Then along came twins (published in The American magazine of September 1933); (3) They put me in jail for singing; (4) Why I quit making funny faces.